Let's start by looking at the makeHttpRequest method.
让我们先了解一下 makeHttpRequest 方法
In the try block shown by these blue highlights,
在以蓝色突出显示 的 try 区块中
we try to make the HTTP request and read the response.
我们尝试发出 HTTP 请求 并读取响应
However, there are some lines in this code that can throw an IO exception.
然而 该代码中的某些行 可能引发 IO 例外
So there's a catch block to catch the exception.
因此 需使用 catch 区块 来捕获这些例外
And finally,
最后
we disconnect the connection if the URL connection is not null.
如果 URL 连接不为空 我们则会断开连接
Now if you look at the documentation for the methods we use,
现在 如果你正在文档中查找 我们使用的这些方法
you'll see that they declare IOException as an expected exception.
你会发现其会将 IOException 声明为预期例外
Take this first line in the try block as an example,
以 try 区块中的 第一行为例
where we call openConnection on the URL object.
调用 URL 对象上的 openConnection
This method is supposed to return a URL connection instance, but
该方法本应返回 一个 URL 连接实例 但是
it could probably throw an IO exception if there's a problem opening
如果在打开连接时出现问题 则可能会引发 IO
the connection.
例外
The URL connection classes connect method could also throw a few
URL 连接类连接方法 同样可能引发几项
exceptions, such as SocketTimeoutException and IOException.
例外 例如 SocketTimeoutException 和 IOException
So going back to our quiz,
因此 回到我们的测验
we catch the IOException in the makeHTTPRequest method.
我们在 makeHTTPRequest 方法中捕获的是 IOException
For the extractFeatureFromJSON() method,
对于 extractFeatureFromJSON() 方法
we have another try catch block surrounding all the JSON parsing code.
我们在所有 JSON 解析代码 的周围设有另一个 try catch 区块
If any step of the parsing throws a JSONException, we catch it and
无论解析过程中任何步骤引发了 JSONException 我们都可将其捕获并
log the error.
记录错误
If we check the documentation, we see that there are many places on our code
如果检查文档 我们会发现 我们代码中的许多地方
that could potentially throw the exception.
都可能 引发例外
For starters,
对于初学者
just calling the JSONObject constructor can throw the JSONException.
仅在调用 JSONObject 构造函数时 可能会引发 JSONException
This can happen if the input string is not properly formatted JSON.
如果输入字符串并不完全符合 JSON 格式要求 则会引发例外
Or the same exception can be thrown when we try to extract the JSONArray.
或者 当我们尝试提取 JSONArray 时 可能会引发相同例外
Also extracting out specific fields can also throw the JSONException,
提取特定字段同样会 引发 JSONException
especially if we try to extract the field whose name does not exist.
尤其是在我们尝试提取 名称不存在的字段时
So back to the quiz, as a result, the answer to the second question is that
回到测验 因此 第二个问题的答案是
instances of JSONException are caught in the extractFeatureFromJSON() method.
在 extractFeatureFromJSON() 方法中捕获的是 JSONException 的实例